www.govt.nz 2016-04-13

# Privacy statement | NZ Government

## Purpose

The purpose of this privacy policy is to let users of Govt.nz (the “Site”) know when we collect personal information and what we do with it. We don't use, share or transfer personal information in connection with the Site except as set out in this policy, or as otherwise set out somewhere on the Site (including in terms linking to the Site). 

## Collection, storage and use

### No need to disclose personal information 

You can use the Site — including completing user research tasks — without disclosing any personal information.

### Your disclosure of personal information 

However, you may choose to disclose personal information to us when you give feedback or in submission forms. This information will be viewable by site administrators, certain Department of Internal Affairs (“DIA”) staff and sometimes third-party contractors who administer, or work on, the Site or who work on special projects with us. Please don't send us sensitive personal information or include any sensitive personal information in submission forms.

### Holding of information

If you provide personal information, it will be held by DIA. It may be shared with third-party contractors to the extent necessary for them to administer or work on the Site or to work on special projects with us. Email addresses are not made available to the public. Unless required by law, we won't publicise the names or email addresses of individuals who provide feedback to us or who provide us with submission forms without their consent.

### Use of personal information 

We'll only use personal information provided to us for the purpose of administering, evaluating and improving the Site, improving our services and communicating with you (including responding to your feedback and information provided in submission forms).

### Feedback

Feedback is important and is used to evaluate and improve the Site. If you provide feedback by email or by using the feedback form, that feedback will be sent to appropriate DIA staff. We may pass on relevant comments to other people within DIA who administer or contribute content to the Site. This could include your email address and other identifying information that you've provided.

### Submission forms

If you provide us with a submission form, that submission form will be sent to appropriate DIA staff. We may pass on relevant content from that submission form to other people within DIA, other government agencies or third parties who administer or are participating in the particular project that the submission form relates to. This could include your email address and other identifying information that you've provided.

## Statistical information and cookies

### Statistical information collected 

We may collect statistical information about your visit to help us improve the Site. This information is aggregated and doesn't identify you personally. It includes:

  * your IP address
  * the search terms you used
  * the pages you accessed on our Site and the links you clicked on
  * the date and time you visited the site
  * the referring site (if any) through which you clicked through to this site
  * your operating system (e.g., Windows XP, Mac OS X)
  * the type of web browser you use (e.g. Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox) 
  * other things like your screen resolution and the language setting of your browser.

### Use of statistical information 

The statistical information referred to above will be viewable by Site administrators and certain other DIA staff. It may also be shared with other government agencies.

### Cookies 

This site generates persistent session cookies for the purpose of monitoring site usage. The cookies don't collect personal information. You can disable them or clear them out of your web browser without affecting your ability to use the Site.

## Records and disclosure statement

### Public Records, Official Information and Parliament 

Your emails and contributions to the site may constitute public records and be retained to the extent required by the Public Records Act 2005. DIA may also be required to disclose those materials under the Official Information Act 1982 or to a Parliamentary Select Committee or Parliament in response to a Parliamentary Question.

## Rights of access and correction

### Your rights

Under the Privacy Act 1993, you have the right to access and to request correction of any of your personal information provided to DIA in connection with your use of this site. If you would like to see or change your personal information DIA has stored, or if you have any concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us at the address below. DIA may require proof of your identity before being able to provide you with any personal information.

The Privacy Officer  
Department of Internal Affairs  
PO Box 805  
Wellington 6140  
Phone: 64 4 495 7200[](tel:044957200)  
Email: [privacy@dia.govt.nz](mailto:privacy@dia.govt.nz)

## Privacy Commissioner 

If you're not satisfied with our response to any privacy-related concern you may have, you can contact the Privacy Commissioner:

Office of the Privacy Commissioner  
PO Box 10-094  
Wellington, New Zealand  
Phone: [04 474 7590](tel:044747590)  
Enquiries Line (from Auckland): [302 8655](tel:093028655)  
Enquiries Line (from outside Auckland): [0800 803 909](tel:0800803909)  
Fax: 04 474 7595  
Email: [enquiries@privacy.org.nz](mailto:enquiries@privacy.org.nz)
